OLGA YUDKIN - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ROBBINSVILLE, NJ | 929-248-9575 | olga.a.yudkin@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using Javascript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, frameworks like Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS. Prior experience in university admissions and recruitment provide an advantage of strong work ethic, excellent communication and teamwork skills, ability to utilize critical thinking and problem-solving skills when approaching problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Vercel, Render, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code, Bootstrap,

Tailwind CSS

Additional Skills: Russian (native), Turkish (conversational), algorithms, data structures, responsive web-design,

agile development methodology

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Thinkful
Software Engineering Program

Online 08/2022 – 02/2023

 Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's, relational databases, algorithms, and data structures, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

 Completed several hands-on role-based and scenario-based projects and virtual labs designed to simulate real-world tasks and challenges.

Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:

Restaurant Reservation Application | Link

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from repositories.
- Technology: React, Node.is, Express, Knex, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, CSS.

Movie Database Application | Link

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

Study Tool Application | Link

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete their perfect deck of study cards.
- Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, HTML and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

Encryption/Decryption Application | Link

- Built to be an encryption/decryption application to communicate and read top-secret messages.
- Created utilizing the test-driven development method.
- Technology: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, Node.js, Bootstrap, Mocha, Chai.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rowan University

Glassboro, NJ

International Student Recruitment Specialist

08/2021 – 08/2022

- Created and delivered presentations to partner agencies and prospective students leading to a 50% improvement over expected lead conversion
- Developed and executed recruitment strategies that increased a number of new international applicants by 78%
- Reviewed and processed 20-30 new student applications per day

 Served as a point of contact for 20+ partner agencies providing day-to-day support, monthly reports and training and successfully resolving 100% of arising issues.

UTP High Schools

New York, NY
International Admission and Recruitment Manager

01/2016– 07/2020

- Planned and managed international recruitment events for a designated region leading to a 100% growth of student numbers from the region.
- Managed international admission process for 2 US high schools, ensuring all applicants are contacted in a timely manner and 100% decisions are issued before the deadline.
- Counseled prospective international students and their families in the school search and application process via email, phone and recruitment events.
- Served as a point of contact for students and their families from a designated region, successfully deescalating 100% of issues without management's involvement.
- Managed and tracked all student admission files in CRM systems (Formsite, Salesforce).

EDUCATION

Thinkful Remote Certificate, Software Engineering 02/2023

Kazan State University (Russia)

Masters of Arts, Education (Specialization: English language teaching)

Kazan, Russia

06/2007